



CONTACT INFORMATION

Phone Number: 438-509-4237 Email: davidholcer@gmail.com Github: github.com/davidholcer LinkedIn: @david-holcer

PROFILE SUMMARY

As a highly motivated college junior, I exemplify my passion for science and mathematics through research and personal projects in computer science and artificial intelligence.

I am an effective team leader with 3 years of experience overseeing NGO's. By tutoring mathematics & computer science I have improved my teaching and communication skills. Being a camp counsellor for 3 summers has strengthened my team working and problem solving abilities.

I am currently seeking employment to consolidate new skills and to apply my current experience within a team setting.

EDUCATION



Bachelor of Science (2019-2023)

Pursuing a joint degree in Honours Mathematics and Computer Science. CGPA: 3.91/4.00

McGill Al Society Bootcamp Course Graduate:

(Sept. 2019 - Nov. 2019)

- Learned fundamental AI concepts through lectures and coding tasks.
- Final project: Emotional analysis of news articles using NLP techniques.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Graphic Design
- Python
- Javascript
- Processing
- Mathematica
- Bash
- English and Spanish Native Speaker
- French Professional Working Proficiency

WORK EXPERIENCE

Camp Miriam (Gabriola Island, BC)

Summer Camp Counselor (June 2019 - Aug. 2019 / June 2020 - Aug. 2020 / June 2021 - Aug. 2021)

- Created and facilitated interactive educational activities for youth aged 9-16.
- Led and communicated within a team of 4-5, directly overseeing the health, safety, and well-being of 10+ campers.
- Responded rapidly and calmly in high pressure situations, finding creative solutions to solve difficult problems.
- Led informal educational discussions about pressing modern-day societal issues.

Geek Education (Remote)

Online Teacher (June 2020 - Oct. 2020)

Taught the Java AP Curriculum to a cohort of 14-year-old students.

- Created challenging coding examples and projects to work through with my students.
- Presented course material in an engaging way, adapting to each student's needs and answering all questions thoroughly.

McGill University (Montreal, QC)

Mathematics Tutor (Jan. 2020 - Present)

- Guided numerous students to mastery in mathematics courses, leading them to excel in their exams through one-on-one sessions.
- Courses included: Calculus 1,2,3; Linear Algebra

Simon Fraser University (Vancouver, BC)

Research Intern (June 2017 - Sept. 2017)

Novel Genomics Data Clustering & Compression Method

- Researched File Compression techniques to compress DNA base pair
- Developed a Markov Chain clustering algorithm used to compare the similarity of different DNA strands through their compressed representations.

Canadian Research Consortium (Vancouver, BC)

Founder (Feb. 2017 - June 2019)

The Canadian Research Consortium was a non-profit organization seeking to further the accomplishments of budding student researchers in STEM fields.

- Headed and oversaw an executive team of 8 people.
- Orchestrated and spearheaded events including a tour of UBC's Biodiversity Museum.
- Arranged sponsorships and partnerships.
- Created and ran social media pages and a website, reaching over 200 students.